Preliminary Guide to the David C. Acheson Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
David C. Acheson papers
1921-1983
MS 1383
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
Preliminary work and research materials of David Acheson, a staff member of the University Development Office until 1980. Includes draft of "Treatment of Yale's Previous Campaign and Development Activities," a history of Yale University's development efforts.
Acheson, David C.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of David C. Acheson in 1983.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Born on November 4, 1921, in Washington, D.C., David Campion Acheson is the son of former Secretary of State, the late Dean Acheson. The younger Acheson graduated from Yale College in 1943 and, after serving in the military during World War II, attended Harvard, from which he received an L.L.B. in 1948. Acheson has worked as an attorney, both in the public and private sectors, for much of his life. He has also served on many government committees and boards of directors. Additionally, Acheson authored Among Friends: The Personal Letters of Dean Acheson (with David McLellan) and a memoir, entitled Acheson Country. In 1943, he married Patricia Castles, with whom he has had three children.
Scope and Contents
Preliminary work and research materials of David Acheson, a staff member of the University Development Office until 1980. Includes draft of "Treatment of Yale's Previous Campaign and Development Activities," a history of Yale University's development efforts.
Lawyers; Acheson, David C.; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale University. Office of Development
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  These papers are the preliminary work and research materials of David Acheson, a staff member of the University Development Office until 1980, who was compiling a history of University Development.
  - David Acheson's project: "Patrons of Learning", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of Development
    - Background material, including 1926-1928 endowment campaign, 1921-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Office of University Development, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Yale Development Board
    - Yale Development Committee, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale Program for Arts and Sciences, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
    - Yale Development Board, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 10)
    - Yale Development Board, 1968-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11 - 19)
    - Yale Development Board, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - References
    - Endowment campaign, 1926-1928 (Box 3, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Peter D. Hall materials, 1974-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - George W. Pierson, Arthur T. Hadley, A. Whitney Griswold, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 24)